chrome over here passion British not to
be confused with these hashes there's
not these hashes we don't record the
videos anymore you have to watch them
live maybe we can make watching the old
videos a perk for subscribers I don't
know if that's possible
I'm not a twitch expert but you know
that might be possible
yeah these brosman I did hear that the
British burned down can I do that can I
make it a perk for subscribers I'll look
into it after this trip I just hear that
the British burned down the White House
at 1812 and that's why we gotta tax them
I'm very amused the British burned down
the White House oh yeah man when I wrote
bubblesort yesterday all those fun where
were we you're eating crappy optimise
optimize crappy that once of chess games
this morning is a good morning I like my
winch afghans okay we have to define the
jacobi the fish bro need to Kate Ganim a
Jacobean ah this one
this one really went too far into the
about your broken website bros
so we don't care about these intrinsic
parameters of the camera look they're
doing it symbolically oh so there's this
thing called senpai which can do
symbolic jacobians I'll install actually
you know what this might not be that bad
right so we have the parameter vector
and we have the measurement vector and
we have the function that relates them
just wait 10 minute so let's see did
some PI install will give senpai
[Music]
calculates the Jacobian matrix
derivative of a vectorial function okay
so this doesn't seem bad so from simp I
import matrix
oh wow and Phi are
whatever on fire well okay so let's just
say x equals matrix a like that's not
right we wanted to find actually respect
to be yeah we're not save those dreams
anymore gotta watch them live bro I
think we don't make that a perk for
subscribers so if you are a subscriber
then you get that perk unless you don't
all right
oh no maybe no sin pi let's go back to
try to understand perk for followers
always if I can do that I'll look right
now you know what let's let's Google
together twitch old streams available to
followers not followers but subscribers
is what I want people who pay me money
five reasons no one is watching their
two extremes let's learn how to be a
twister you just launched your channel
no schedule we have a schedule we
communicate my stream is not about my
audience sorry people and I'm certainly
sure as hell doubt promoting my channel
expression for the rotation matrix based
on the Rodrigues formula oh well that's
something we're gonna have to solve dude
I could be a twitch stop I'm gonna wear
a wig twitch thats twitch that's okay so
that you're getting it never be like
loser
everything is winning I'm in San
Francisco have you seen it kind of
modeled well I moved to New York when I
moved to New York my house can feel it
man I already know what you know what's
nice to have to come hey guys it's gonna
be sweet
okay where we were watching tutorials
again so we go right to that that
keynote one was pretty good well the Mac
App Store all I hear they're trying to
make the Mac App Store better I have an
advertisement okay
we learned yesterday how we were gonna
estimate the Hessian from the Jacobian
the hash shouldn't equals the jacobian
transpose times w that's that's good so
we just need to define the Jacobi that's
where you were yesterday
yes okay five 3d features so they're
putting the features there the images
there and they have camera calibrations
so we don't we still put the camera
calibration in no no there we go that
much okay so what is this a 1 a 2 okay
so those are observations so on the each
row what is a parameter and each no each
column is a parameter and each row oh
thank you thank you now danger 7 thank
you for subscribing these are
observations and these are parameters
and like so then this is the jacobian so
so basically we're asking the question
what's the derivative of a with respect
to a-1 which I don't think is anything
right I mean it's not like if you move
the camera your observations gonna
change well maybe a well no okay this is
the point yeah if I move the point it
certainly will change and if I move the
camera it'll change as well that's the
same picture they use the same picture
except they made this look terrible okay
we haven't even written out the Jacobian
yeah we haven't even gotten to any of
this yet cameras for features okay so
the other problem is we have to
parameterize our mr. Oh a o40
thank you for subscribing to my channel
no you can't get this hoodie anywhere
this is this is the softest merch in the
game after maverick March which is the
real Sophos merch in the game and who I
stole that from okay so we do need to
we do need to deal with how we're gonna
parameterize rotation and I do think we
have to parameterize it as Euler angles
okay the problem with a rotation matrix
is rotation has three degrees of freedom
and a rotation matrix has nine so you'd
have to figure out some way to ensure
stuff about it figure out what I would
do to us
let's free GG well we're you guys
reading the avocado
not this stuff you open it over here
freshly
3g2 ow
stuff types
let's see how they parameterize rotation
is what I'm interested in here Oh edge
lots of ex-wife Wow look at these people
make a little bigger for you guys
lots of XYZ I don't even know wait X Y Z
okay then in your eyes oh plus so I'm
not gonna know really what that does
what's a wittle girl too lazy
camera and XYZ prime the vertex I see
three okay so this is a vertex draw
triangle Wow
I don't know g2o supported OpenGL that's
kind of nice I used sublime to read code
reading code and vim is hard but I write
code again and then I read code and
sublime no no I've kind of better this
way for a long time alright let's see if
there's any information it's just like
drawing stuff isn't even anything
givers offset that rotation so it
doesn't look like it's a 3x3
vertex I see 30 okay vector six internal
to vector mqt to compact quaternion ooh
what's a compact quaternion oh so it's a
quarter neon with only through he sheds
cuz they normalize it I say from Euler
to Euler the first day I found it to a
quarter neon I don't really use plugins
too hard to keep straight
alright this stuff kind of makes sense
they're using compact quaternions
not even gonna I'm not even I don't know
pass some time they're doing it here
they call them W I don't know why they
call them W but all right so get point
location guesses plus come on keep them
in order don't weigh they're just
passing the frame so passing the frames
some points with our frames passed in
frames oh cool
get poses and I think if I want the
translation it's like yeah we get this
wrong wait wait guys we're gonna try to
do this these are columns when I select
something the first thing I get
if I do like sub-3 I should get the
third row that's right so if I want the
third column I do this yeah this is T
now for our I can do this right from now
on if you ask about the keyboard and
you're not a subscriber you're bad
who gives a let me tell you
something about tools guys step one
don't be a tool you can try step 2
now if shell is computer anyway um step
two tools don't matter only your mind
matters and unless you're a tool it's
not a tool don't be a tool and so we
used to call each other in high school
you're a tool right tool it's like funny
is there a good insult I like because
one of these days we'll watch battle rap
rod why did why couldn't the guy would
Bennett if he named like Paul see me to
Paul I wouldn't have to spell it wrong
Paul all right so we can say good job
you equals that w tools don't be a loser
don't be poor oh such good life advice
you know every parent should tell their
kid that good son when you grow up don't
be a loser and don't be poor okay
what happened that dudes paper I like
that paper
we got paper we were reading that PhD Oh
a modern synthesis what the hell is a
synthesis it sounds like one of those
like critical theory words this wasn't
the paper we had yesterday
oh cool bird leg back divergence mom
it's just some kind of interesting to
read Triggs
just be aware and enjoy your life you'll
pay me $2,000 cash for 5% of twitch slim
that's a good deal you get a 5 for what
5% do you want which which part of the
code do you want ah this
to Taylor expansions tailors and
Hessians bundle adjustment what was that
guy's PhD I liked it
bundle adjustment toriel
Oh beautiful Mondrian linear
least-squares sparse matters bros t and
s III yeah this means something the
Euclidean group for SC 3 is used in the
kinematics of a rigid body wikipedia
they can't just explain math like normal
people whose a lie group like money is
matter food is matter money doesn't
really matter either but you know it's a
good way to keep school alright you
think about it like points and how much
money you have is like how many points
you have cuz I bet money is actually
useful for anything it's just a good way
to say like you know you can decide who
has more points right and like I'm not
saying points or everything but like
would you trust someone who did have a
lot of points right that's what I'm
saying right like you come in a
counter-strike server you see someone's
kills the death ratio is just near
you then they tell their good kind of
strike I've know you believe him right
like someone says they're good at life
but they don't have that many points I
don't know if you believe them right
just make sensible
okay
what happened that paper we were reading
yesterday bundle adjustment you know
that one what does it say
PhD terrain napping oh yeah it was this
one but of course we're not gonna
purchase it we're gonna download it free
love free why do they call it Taylor
no Brooke Taylor
Oh some reason I thought she'd be hot
but it's some old dudes in Britain
like a Maclaurin series it's a linear
they could even expand things into like
big polynomials and / tellers not
look like Taylor Swift I know I'm very
sad about this though
don't gather no upset all right so where
were we
okay up up up up up here we go here we
are okay the camera parameters also
they're using wacky w let's put T first
cool sweet into X zero I've got a pen T
x0 I've got a pen Gabi yeah
all right now we have a parameter vector
and a residual vector that's complete so
if only I could hatch in them
so now these aren't an order of ID right
like I don't want you to leave Friday
yeah cool
well we can change this residual
function a little bit to not use this
magical F dot pose anymore what we want
to say I have a to R to be helping so
that have this thing have the code to go
back from Rodriguez right so f dot IG
okay so we can say same info when I want
to say T W equals subway points times 3
plus that's that ID times X well that's
brutally copy and paste that brutal
was it a song cuz you only heard half of
it bro don't worry for show you company
we're coming that's coming
[Music]
[Laughter]
we're trying to call lovely that was the
other one alright guys so I don't know
what's trying to be called here this is
that numpy and diri object is not
callable date is just a number
yeah his home state MP dot omega x omega
Oh got a plus gotta put your plus as a
michael invalid value and countering
multiply beta zero doesn't rotate I'm
going to do about that
okay it's small now if I change this to
actually use my URT I'm gonna work so
the problem is we are getting the frame
poses from this magical outside place
and it's never gonna work for my
adjustment so let's try that now
[Music]
expansion for the rotation matrix based
on the Rodrigues formula some of them 0
0 1 0 0
like those zero zero well I just don't
want to do about that right W has the
following form
I wrote this right there for mrs.
divided by theta
there's equations wrong
right now des see this you're right that
we need a library here because I want
this to be differentiable
I think it will work I do yes it just
sucks the rotations are like this we
have to parameterize it like this cannot
copy sequence with size - no
this is from making coups I know that
one's good
cool it seems to work
oh well I'll do that see if they're in
the same ballpark cool in the same
ballpark hello alright so he really
shouldn't use crappy SCV two functions
there but we can do some things like
[Music]
yes subscribe to my boys what don't
by Netflix don't buy media companies
guys
the media is evil okay cool
TW p is less media is a scam guys don't
pay friends don't let friends be media
don't read the media don't look at the
media don't think about the media
they're bad it's a mind virus
you're proud how do I break
cannot be broadcast together
yes I disabled to Judeo our time yes the
past is the past right just broke
because I move that to there that's a
joke if you capture video I'll see you a
copyright infringer let's say I got a
lawyer's brow
yeah we won't talk about stuff
you know watching porn every Denis oh I
don't think it's bad hey probably yeah
it probably has like best us all up late
though at this point were already kind
of messed up it's like any addiction
just figure out a manage it things it
doesn't take over your life as long as
that's the thing right I mean that has
to take difference between like you know
drug addiction or drug use right like
does it negatively affect your life
that's what you have to ask yourself
about porn as well that's what you have
to ask yourself about the media that's
the thing man he all these people like
oh I'm so anxious man I saw something
that said Putin was gonna start World
War 3 yeah where'd you see that you
talked to Putin friends with them oh no
you saw it in the media that's right and
why is the media want you to feel that
way that's the question you gotta ask
man and premium porn is not a scam I'm
totally a fan I mean at least the media
isn't like that it's content right um
porn doesn't really like the second that
has a gentle pushing porn
the second they try to make porn more
addictive than it already is
like there's no like looking god I mean
maybe they could maybe do it I mean they
could maybe figure out how to get you in
like a negative like anxiety spiral with
porn and then the the pointer to
shoot but I haven't seen them do that
man
Vaughn - yeah but really like kids look
at what the media does to your minds
like like if you read me if you don't
make me do this doesn't apply to you but
if you read media I want you to think
about like your mental state before you
read media and after you read media
right
okay
so now we want to figure out how to add
a Jacobian eyes this matrix like what we
want to do to do compute the Jacobian of
this your metal state before and after
fortune there's already some Fortran
kids all right so we want to compute the
Jacobian of this so residuals are a
function that you know f of X equals the
prime if you can figure out how to
compute the Jacobi of that basically
what we want to do is we want to alter
the vector X such that
so is this gonna work we do the gradient
or maybe that works very well yeah
yes POTUS we don't need residual X minus
B to some square side cool this work
source is on an umpire in our scale Oh
[Music]
Rodriguez oh let's see okay let's see if
we can write this without the Rodriguez
what is this do
rotation matrix to Euler angles
you came at the same time every day
aside from actually liking your audience
that's something you can do to improve
twitch viewership to improve your twitch
app I read a tutorial about this this
morning on twitch this is all crappy so3
oh not to be confused with se3 they go
through a quick tourney on to the CV to
have a definition of this crap inverse
transformation can also be done easily
yeah whoa jacobians interesting yeah
okay here's the problem it's doing that
/ again but yeah that's the exact
equation I wrote out
but what if R is zero then the norm of R
is zero and then you're left with that
crap again my special K set
because that is exactly what's written
here
and I wrote this already you guys watch
me to do it okay they do cancel ours
I don't understand why this for God's
punishing my okay it works the only
problem is in the zero case ants
or even by an angle-theta around a fixed
axis specified by the unit vector
so you look at this expansion this
expansion doesn't have any / zit
see the problem still / is here okay so
this is kind of cute um look they do it
without access math square root n P dot
access to access it so that's
effectively the same thing essentially a
cuter way to write that so they
normalize the access say
that is sad right there okay so see they
talk about how it has to be a unit
vector basically
/ X it's the same crap could put a
stupid non-linearity in it like okay I
want this just I want this to just go
away if theta zero you can do that and
that's probably correct and to be loved
this unreliable phone numerical
instabilities works most of the time
okay band you get a timeout that's right
and if people timeout I did say the
keyboard thing was a bad question that
is very clear so mega is just zero see
that's the thing right that / doesn't
even matter because that whole matrix is
full of zeros just multiply zeros by
something
the problem is man's man perfect
[Laughter]
what do you think of my fix guys there
are tests
sending an array element with a sequence
what are we doing sending an array
element with a sequence
oh okay that kind of makes sense yeah so
that stuff's not allowed
the input arrays must have the same a
lip dimension so we probably try out
clothes that yeah it's computing the
derivative class enumerate returns a
results with an error set aw
class enumerate we're trying to resolve
with Marisa well that's a great error
love it okay so some of my crap is not
differentiable which of my crap nobody
knows well hang on think about something
else here MP dot R T so that's just R T
so 3 by 4 matrix dot that right so I do
think it's the same thing as just saying
that's right cetera is like you try to
write that matrix taught that
differentiable
No well okay there's a lot of man's
man's Oh divided by zero encounter in
double scalars well this could be a
divide by zero the same trick our
numerical stability don't divide by zero
kids it's bad for computers no no bad
thing you divided by zero yeah now we
have Nance we divide by zero and we get
Nance
let's make apps a little big well
actually the army is no way no that has
to be positive the other one could be
negative divided by zero encountered in
double scalars Nance all right well that
turned out to not be so necessary got a
parameterize your correctly
Wow look how small that error is so good
good mean no wait yeah do that
square unless it's just a mean of okay
it's tiny and still yours take the mean
gives one degree 10 will be minus 10
right
we're out of monta right amante and the
optimizer still a piece of look it
divides by zero and now we get
we want to compute this symbolically
my favorite writer working we saw that
as much higher when I mess it up
okay
the idea exciting that you matter
because you're doing a projection it's
kind of interesting
can actually do better than that so
really we just need to differentiate
that one function symbolically and then
stick that in a lot of places so point
TW this is so Point has three TW has six
he has to go back to our bundle
adjustment it's that paper that I
liked no this one the bundle adjustment
to Kobe and matrix okay
so I don't know about camera constrains
I don't think we need any of those but
these projection constraints this is the
jacobian so yeah this is this is where
you get to by knowing from right
actually I don't know don't think they
are now but you see easy oh because this
is this is the jacobian this is the
jacobian of nine parameters with respect
to two parameters if you like stick them
together it doesn't really matter so
it's like f of you know some nine
parameter thing
and that determines like the external
encoding why do we use jacobian well
because the paper says to know so
Jacobian basically I want to ask the
question how do I alter these things how
do i order my input vector to make these
projection constraints more true this is
the question that we're asking here
because that's what I can change I can
move my cameras around and I can move my
three space points around and these
constraints are all fixed right so here
we you know we have a measurement vector
of your parameter vector vector so the
I'm trying to get the Jacobian of others
the way to actually talk about this but
like it's this with respect to this now
I think if I could do it for just one
numerically I think I can just like kind
of write that out and once that's right
now I just need to hit it all over the
place like that all right
so we have some big matrix it's like
yeah it's like this shape by this shape
let's make sure I got this right
okay so each one of those things is
gonna be a column so I should did that
as a row so I did that backwards yeah
that makes sense okay so I can define
the Jacobian cool but the problem is we
have to actually get the Jacobian we
have to actually take the Jacobian of
this thing let's see if we can use simp
I to do that the question is like what
is J proj I don't know if that thing
that we were using like that work okay
so let's see you end up at five
work grad only applies to real-valued ah
try Jacobi and all they even have one
called Jacobian from Otto grad important
to Colby in all let's try that
Oh being Raj all right so the the
gradient only applies to scalar value
output functions jacobians worked on
vector oh it's praying something well
that's not right this is Jay shape just
not right like that's not the right
shape but maybe cuz it's stupid and
can't handle it maybe it just used that
as extra parameters right so you can
write this pretty easily just say I'll
call it
ptew well quality so before and after so
ill-fortune kids now basically what we
want to say is gonna concatenate these
two arrays
even use concatenate like that but let's
say projects to position or you ah
perfect look at the shape of the
Jacobian now it's two by nine and that's
what we want so then we just have to put
the thingies in the right place
oh ho ho we're rich guys we're rich the
numerical Jacobian of the projection
function what does all be really care
about I mean okay be kind of nice to
symbolically but I don't know if that
matters
um this is slow boy slow what that is oh
it's still getting zeros yeah I think I
want to compute the numerical code I
think if I use Empire I don't need to
write this PGW don't really matter
like it's easy it's better to think
about it this way
all right so for each basically you see
oh there's an 2 by 9 for each row in the
matrix so this returns a 2 by 9 thing
I'm doing a Jacobian now but let's try
this Empire coat
this is going to compute the Jacobian
symbolically matter like I don't care
check Jacobian respect to x and y okay
senpai all right some block matrix is
fine let me just speak that as a matrix
matrix a matrix symbol here we go now
so say if you got your equals s P dot
matrix are we going to need to redefine
means to be seven powers that work array
takes two one positional argument but
two were given I don't know what that
means
I mean I guess maybe we don't want to
use numpad you want to use like simp I
don't know if I can do that one senpai
has no attribute dot well it hasn't have
to be a square root we don't we don't
actually need to do dot there we can say
SP dots so does that work well senpai
has no attributes some fine already not
explicitly cash
and object has no attribute so I'm
pretty sure some PI does have side it
doesn't have dot array takes one
positional argument but two we're giving
it through that okay seven PI matrix
multiplication oh yes I think maybe we
could just say times and I think you do
that numpy - oh look at that
that looks like some all right so
this is symbolic Jacobian look at that
symbolic Jacobian guys actually we're
doing a symbolically I might not need
that EPS yeah okay good
so that's the very complex symbolic
Jacobian
so we can say juv okay now simply has a
way to actually compile that make it
nice look at that that look right yeah
uses autorap crap oh why am i straight
guys why is a stupid question
why do people do things I mean like I'm
like I'm nowhere near as nice as like we
should find there would be about this
but like yeah watch what you'd find this
thing about like like you know he asked
the question like how to make this work
and like you know he's very polite with
the journalists but like it's a stupid
question like what do you mean how two
magnets work but like with respect to
what Paul is just like invisible rubber
bands pulling things together
Nothe stop at a magnets work go study
Maxwell's equations right and like aside
from that there's no real so why I mean
don't question like what do you mean by
why unclassifiable statement this is
much more interesting what does that
mean oh just trying to compile Fortran
great it doesn't build
okay well that was good while it lasted
there's other ways to use autorap I
think you simp I'd coma its impose
really great but it does always work
okay right language equal see back-end F
2 pi and language C are incompatible
okay
back then equals cipher
no module name sighs oh oh oh now again
history and small side well I you want
me to keep if you enjoy my twitch
channel please subscribe and send me
bits and if I see that I'm making money
off this I will continue to stream
indefinitely
so I'm scripted value is neither already
nor pointer what what are you
complaining about
ptew like didn't work that looks like
totally fine see to me
okay can I see the C code being
generated oh man you funkify oh this
looks so let's try you funcle' oh oh i
think i have to pass in don't get pass
in something to autorap
try you funkify maybe you bug the
flowers I feel like I have to pass in
well let's actually first just try that
with I just found a PDW here I think it
doesn't know I think I should that has
to be an array to know you funkify pass
it Kiki W and Jake watch mmm error
passing double to parameter C this is
what sucks about simp I like I don't
know what's wrong now you ready this
Python there's a way to do that
we need binary function we'll try the
last one binary function your my final
hope f J fry huh back to this Fortran
that looks okay to me
except for like what is all this maybe
doesn't look okay
okay the only thing I think that could
be bad maybe is this NP dot array that
work like I can play write that in a
better way it's thinking about what I'm
actually doing there that date is fine
good MP dot array parentheses like
matter even though this finish this
doesn't can I call it I mean I can call
it what I call like Jake rods with like
and that zero line I kind of like my
plus epsilon so we can so sin pi is a
lot like the ATO in which it's total
garbage matte mall object is not
callable
was that to come up again
c-code okay I pack them somewhere
senpai senpai printing see coatsy coach
any of this other stuff supposed to work
right print some C code I can't leave
read it and other than that C code and
you don't we they say about C codes
right fast and fast all fast this C not
supported in C immutable dense matrix I
have an idea that's what this NP array
is doing okay if this is the source of
my problems how can I write this in a
simple way
I say SP dot matrix
looks marginally better it has less
weird big parentheses thingies autorap
good well last Wow
pow 22 I mean that's sketchy come on
come on you funkify know bad argument
double comma 200 and classify all the
statement okay well another that works
fit our mat mole object is not callable
I just don't know let's go
well assistant principal varnish right
this no different so it's not even that
that looks like the simplest
now at least that doesn't work okay so
we've like structural failures Auto funk
results subscripted value is not an
array pointer or vector I don't know why
do the Fortran fat or Fortran for
Fortran failures on the classifiable
okay
so for some reason is just not getting
Auto all right let's just let's find a
simp I on a rap example oh this does not
work if I use matrix symbol have to use
matrix symbol I think I can say B dot
symbol just create them all um XP YP z Y
X T Y Z W XW YW z
cymbals a little it's idx crap we put
them in a vector does that work simple
object is not subscript it's a symbol
that is a symbol the patent symbols were
symbols
it was the Iranian to see cannot add
simple ass mutable dense matrix and
class 2.0 well it kind of makes sense
right
some 5x
some pie matrix yeah really
that work capital m ha matrix size
mismatch oh well that's good at least I
should be a little edge a bit vector
like that's sensible at least okay fine
you can't add that to that I'm simple no
you don't want vectors though
all crap does that work I don't know no
but okay see how we're defining the
symbols explicitly now this is better
wait how does that make sense
our x PT w3 should that work unsupported
types for a list and add okay I don't
like this anymore this work add matrix
analyst this is crap Auto funk results
CJ providers like the function
interesting
[Music]
it just calls it Auto funk results right
and that's the problem in my stream
today until I fix this all right arms
I know those friends don't actually do
anything
now with the question what if I supposed
by Jake watch that so the first argument
must be a simp Ison this is impossible
this is not a senpai simple which
doesn't really make sense like that is
right though can I just print the code
I'm gonna do that before with C code
print me C code great like that's what C
code where's that set
matrix you funkify that to the house the
yard oh the code
I'll expand you can't return a vector
that's better
so let's just say Ju and Jamie
and we were both too so if I did this
right I should be able just didn't like
returning a vector that's not a problem
okay with that Ju Sub Zero
not nice all right yeah compiled
copious okay so remember how we have a 2
by 9 matrix now instead of having 2 by 9
matrix we have 2 1 by 9 inches but you
know what they say that's a 2 by 1
matrix buffer has wrong number of
dimensions expected to got one oh that's
fine all right all right come on they
can progress man well it's going to be
passed in zeroes really do that oh and
let's put this after back on the crash
crash
wait a second I pass in nine I get one
out
that's not right
[Music]
it's a scam oh well yeah because I'm
look at this time I'm not actually
taking the jacobian yet that's just to
compute the projection function which we
should actually be able to use logic oh
yeah that's actually just the function
but like so I could pass on that
function but it doesn't matter
let's figure out the Jacobian now we
want to say X proj dot Jack hold the end
Raj that's not even that's just a
projection function that mall has no
attribute data type not understood
we'll see if it works when I come with
this crap out
after all this
this library sucks you know it was good
autograft I like the Auto grad don't
when the auto grad was it couldn't
compute a symbolic Jacobian which we
need to do if you don't do it symbolic
it's doing like some numerical
automatically differentiate I like dotto
grad okay well this matrix symbol
doesn't seem to work the X to Y to Z now
we will go a little bit beautiful dense
matrix a twist
you're showing that's a list that is a
list right simple matrix it actually
works it's no less it's a matrix I don't
see that this is what I understand
okay like that better maybe time for a
listing man well at least that's better
just add this back data type not inter
stud I want line that is
oh okay that's fine
mall has no answer to luke Jacobian well
since I show everyone that but still
mall
sweet so now we can get JP JT and each
one of these should be a three by two
matrix okay you okay cool but that's
exciting right take a look look at how
exciting this is each one of these
should be a two by three matrix and they
should be just to bring it full circle
it was a good paper no these these two
by three matrix so like this one here
should be JP this should be JT and this
should be JW if we did it right I think
I can discrete this matrix once you buy
the code a little bit
[Music]
drogyn missing two required arguments in
the bathroom about 20 more minutes to
streaming hopefully we'll actually get
those jacobians compiled on computer
no I do want more I want some coffee
whatever I want but warm coffee guys I
haven't had warm coffee and so long all
right let's see if Aldo raps gonna work
we oughta wrap this watch that works no
oh yeah did something right
so now if I JP so if I did this right no
no no so I have to pass in the points
this should return a two by three matrix
I think maybe quiet argument P Wow Wow
that's why so I pass on the point there
and a 2 3 with 2 or 3 2 by 3 2 by 3 oh
okay fine 2 by 3 2 by 3 ah yeah boys us
2 by 3
all right who's excited in tiles
I am the social media coordinator for
come ad that is true okay now I redefine
frauds or something oh just take some
crap now et this works anymore to be
honest yeah matrix sighs oh gosh hang on
oh maybe I need to just
because it's times 22 and at times to
their what else what
I might even compile
[Music]
yeah matrix Isaac okay because the
problem I don't know why P is a weird
matrix size yeah what if instead of a
SUV
huge utility vehicle I would settle for
Starbucks
if someone bring me Starbucks right now
you're pretty happy well it's a Fortran
object oh my favorite kind of object
okay let's try a PV here so now we're
actually calling the the functions this
takes a long time I hate when things are
slow oh god I hate when things are slow
to projects and I call oh yeah I don't
all right so now for each one of these
we can actually compute just I got to
list here here we can get like JP equals
F JP pz w JT j w JT f JW right
each one of these if I did it right
should be a three by three matrix and
then we'll just have to put them in the
right place and then we'll have a
Jacobean look at that some of them are
non-stop but that does sound like it
tomorrow problem today we learned what
to Kobe and so are we well we knew what
you co beans were yesterday but today we
wrote the we wrote these
beautiful rotation functions and they
returned things that are the right shape
and that have numbers in them so if
they're the right shape and they have
numbers in them you're probably doing
pretty well for yourself well I mean
I'll go to Starbucks guys maybe we'll
say have a job it'll work
look it up it's our nods look at
them nods
they're going to nan nan we just don't
put it in please leave them zeros right
here but yeah so well I guess I'll write
this now because why not and then we're
done
so we can save it J so I is the point ID
you notice the frame ID so first we
address the row in the matrix the row o
which we're gonna die the X for again I
think I don't know if we accidentally
just gonna same j j x 2 plus 2 so that's
the row in the matrix the column in the
matrix is of course the point ID which
is this crap here let's write the same
equal JP oh yeah now we set JP now we
just need to set JT and J you so those
are the same it's the same indexing as
yes that's so ugly
take your nap my ex : f by DX plus three
and this one is Fi the X plus 3 : fi DX
plus 6 now we have a big J to do because
we did it right this kind of less crappy
yeah we have it to Kobe end is it to
write Jacobian tune in tomorrow to find
out we stream every day because it is
every day bro and maybe you will listen
to that song on the way out
Jay Paul's encounter track me
don't watch the media it's a great song
double-check an iTunes right here oh you
show up for that March thumbs up yeah
he's talking about a list of violate
Yelp selling like a god Church we got to
turn it off before we get to Nick Crump
then Nick Crompton is terrible
Jake Paul Jay Paul oh man oh no no no we
also have to look at one more tweet oh
oh is it oh yes yes this tweet this
tweet bro it's funny oh all right thank
you thank you please like and subscribe
and make sure to send me money
cuz I'm poor I got afford coffee just
kidding I'm not poor what do you think I
am but I do love money so if you could
send me that that would be great if you
are amused if you like this content if I
look at my money and I'm in a hundred
dollars this week I'm like I'm gonna
keep twitch streaming if I look at my
money and I made less than $100 I'm
probably still gonna keep twitch
streaming but but thank you for the
one bit I feel like yeah thank you off
the cam girls you know they always do it
I should watch more cowgirls and be
better at shilling and and being a
twitch stop alright alright bye bye - a
cheese bye bye where's my broadcaster